# Rasool Shaik

# Mulesoft Developer

- x rasoolshaik4803@gmail.com
- +917569450596
- Hyderabad

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rasool-shaik



### **Profile**

**4+** Years of IT experience in **TCS** with **3+** years of experience in **MuleSoft Development** (Mule ESB, RAML1.0) & 1 Year of Experience into Microsoft Biztalk support.Experience in MuleSoft AnyPoint Platform, Enterprise Service Bus and API Management.Having experience in designing Flows, Sub Flows, and Exception handling strategies, Data Weave transformation and Mule Expression Language(MEL).Experience in designing and developing RESTful APIs using AnyPoint studio and AnyPoint platform.

## **Professional Experience**

Mulesoft Developer, TCS: Project 1: Cignis Roles & Responsibilities:

08/2023 – present | Hyderabad, India

- Developed RAML for REST API using Design center.
- Extensively used Mule components like HTTP, Salesforce connectors, Database and Data weave.
- Involved in converting data formats such as XML and JSON by using Data weave.
- Used APIKIT Router to generate flows based on the RAML.
- Used Database connectors to connect with respective systems using Mule ESB.
- Extensively used Mule Debugger to debug the xml flows and wrote M unit test cases using features like mocking, and assert conditions based different sets of data.
- Experience in Deploying/Managing Mule flows to Cloud Hub.
- Used Anypoint Platform to deploy application to the Runtime Manager.

# Mulesoft Developer, TCS: Project 2: OBMS Roles & Responsibilities:

02/2021 – 08/2023 | Hyderabad, India

- Created Mule Flows using End Point Connectors & Components using Mule ESB to integrate Client/server systems.
- Used Anypoint Platform to deploy application to the Runtime Manager.
- Backup restore database, managing servers, managing clients, automating administration tasks.
- Performing the database upgradations from lower version to higher versions and database refreshes from production to development.

**BizTalk Support,** *TCS : Project 3 : KAH* **Roles & Responsibilities:** 

12/2019 - 01/2021 | Hyderabad, India

- Monitoring Running Service Instances, Suspended Service Instances & Spool count daily and sending the report to client.
- Monitoring Receive locations & Send Ports of all interfaces.
- Worked on Schemas, Maps, Pipelines, Adapters and Orchestrations.
- Resolve daily environment issues, network issues, dead lock issues, data issues and space issues.

#### Education

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics & Communications),

06/2015 - 04/2019 | Rajampet, India

Annamacharya Institute of Technology and Sciences

## **Certifications**

Mulesoft L1 Developer L1

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals az-900

#### **Tools Used**

• Integration : Mule ESB (4.x) ,Anypoint Studio, Microsoft Biztalk Server 2010.

Data Bases: MySQL, OracleWeb Services: SOAP, REST

• Markup Languages : HTML, XML and JSON

Operating System: WindowsOther Tools: Postman

• Version control : Git Hub

### **Declaration**

I do hereby declare that above particulars of information and facts stated are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Mahammed Rasool Shaik Hyderabad